<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Disembodied</name>
		<source>Grim Hollow - The Players Guide</source>
		<update version="0.1.0">
			<file name="race-disembodied.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Grim-Hollow/refs/heads/main/Races/race-disembodied.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- Disembodied Race -->
	<element name="Disembodied" type="Race" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACE_DISEMBODIED">
		<description>
			<p>To cast one’s mind out amongst the outer planes is the dream of many an arcane spellcaster. In recent memory, none have come closer to that dubious honor than the lost city of Ulmyr’s Gate. Founded by a group of ambitious wizards who chafed under the limitations imposed upon them by government bureaucracy, Ulmyr’s Gate boasted free study for all mages who sought sanctuary within its walls. The Great College quickly became a lodestone for mages of every stripe from across the empire, and for a brief moment there existed a golden age of magic.</p>
            <p>That dream came crashing down one night when the founding mages of Ulmyr’s Gate attempted a massive conjuration ritual intended to part the veil and create a permanent portal to the Ethereal Plane. It didn’t work. Instead their magic caused a massive rift in the very fabric of reality, and in an instant the entire city tipped into the void between worlds. The entire city was presumed dead, the Arcanist Inquisition railed against the hubris of those tampering in things man was not meant to know, and life in the Empire moved on.</p>
            <p>Years later, stories surfaced of strange people being sighted in the region where Ulmyr’s Gate once stood. These people seemed oddly blurred or indistinct, and some reports said they vanished right in front of witnesses’ eyes. Gradually it became clear that these poor souls were the survivors of the Ethereal Rift, now trapped between worlds and trying to retain their tenuous grasp on the Material Plane.</p>
			<h4>DISEMBODIED TRAITS</h4>
            <p>You possess certain traits as a result of the magical mishap that trapped you between worlds. The disembodied are a collection of races that were in Ulmur’s Gate when the accident occured. Because of this, you can choose what race you appear as. This also affects some features below, such as your height. Unless specified, you do not gain any racial features from your origin race.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Intelligence score increases by 2 and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> The disembodied mature at a much slower rate than their humanoid equivalent, and their life expectancy is drastically higher, with not a single disembodied having passed due to old age.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> The disembodied tend towards no particular alignments.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> You still possess the height of your former humanoid self, but your nearly insubstantial nature has drastically reduced your weight to a quarter of your original weight. Your size is the same it was before the accident.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Fade Away.</em></strong> On your turn, as an action, you can fade from the Material Realm and disappear into the ethereal plane. While you remain faded away, you cannot interact with the Material Plane, and effects on the Material Plane cannot interact with you, including spells and creatures. However, you can move and hear as normal, and see everything in shades of grey.</p>
            <p>This effect lasts for 1 minute, or until you use a bonus action to end it early. When the effect ends, you reappear in the Material Plane, in the closest unoccupied space you disappeared from. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Planar Outcast.</em></strong> You may cast the feather fall spell once per day, targeting yourself only. When you reach 3rd level, you may cast the blur spell once per day. When you reach 5th level, you may cast the blink spell once per day. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Arcane Origins.</em></strong> You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write two languages of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<!-- Ability Score Increase (Intelligence +2, Dexterity +1) -->
			<stat name="intelligence" value="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
            <stat name="dexterity" value="1" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<!-- Tasha's Cauldron of Everything: Custom Ability Score Increase (+2 and +1, or three +1's) -->
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +2 (Disembodied)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Disembodied)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" number="3" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI" />

			<!-- Size (You can choose the size and height) -->
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Size (Disembodied)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_SMALL|ID_INTERNAL_RACIAL_TRAIT_MEDIUM" />

			<!-- Speed (30 ft. walking) -->
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />

            <!-- Fade Away -->
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACIAL_TRAIT_DISEMBODIED_FADE_AWAY" />

            <!-- Planar Outcast -->
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACIAL_TRAIT_DISEMBODIED_PLANAR_OUTCAST" />

            <!-- Arcane Origins -->
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACIAL_TRAIT_DISEMBODIED_ARCANE_ORIGINS" />

			<!-- Languages (Choose two) -->
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Disembodied)" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="2" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<!-- Tasha's Cauldron of Everything: Customized Language -->
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language" number="2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
		</rules>
	</element>


	<!-- Fade Away Trait -->
	<element name="Fade Away" type="Racial Trait" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACIAL_TRAIT_DISEMBODIED_FADE_AWAY">
		<description>
			<p>On your turn, as an action, you can fade from the Material Realm and disappear into the ethereal plane. While you remain faded away, you cannot interact with the Material Plane, and effects on the Material Plane cannot interact with you, including spells and creatures. However, you can move and hear as normal, and see everything in shades of grey.</p>
            <p>This effect lasts for 1 minute, or until you use a bonus action to end it early. When the effect ends, you reappear in the Material Plane, in the closest unoccupied space you disappeared from. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Action">
			<description>On your turn, you can fade from the Material Realm and disappear into the ethereal plane. While you remain faded away, you cannot interact with the Material Plane, and effects on the Material Plane cannot interact with you, including spells and creatures. However, you can move and hear as normal, and see everything in shades of grey.
            This effect lasts for 1 minute, or until you use a bonus action to end it early. When the effect ends, you reappear in the Material Plane, in the closest unoccupied space you disappeared from.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <!-- Planar Outcast -->
	<element name="Planar Outcast" type="Racial Trait" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACIAL_TRAIT_DISEMBODIED_PLANAR_OUTCAST">
		<description>
			<p>You may cast the feather fall spell once per day, targeting yourself only. When you reach 3rd level, you may cast the blur spell once per day. When you reach 5th level, you may cast the blink spell once per day. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You may cast the feather fall spell once per day, targeting yourself only. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
			<description level="3">You may cast the feather fall spell once per day, targeting yourself only. You may cast the blur spell once per day. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
			<description level="5">You may cast the feather fall spell once per day, targeting yourself only. You may cast the blur and blink spells once per day. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEATHER_FALL" level="1" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLUR" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <!-- Arcane Origins -->
	<element name="Arcane Origins" type="Racial Trait" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide" id="ID_GFG_GHPG_RACIAL_TRAIT_DISEMBODIED_ARCANE_ORIGINS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />     
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>