<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Oath of Pestilence</name>
        <source>Grim Hollow - The Players Guide</source>
        <update version="0.1.0">
            <file name="Paladin-Pestilence.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Julitutu/Grim-Hollow/refs/heads/main/Subclasses/Paladin-Pestilence.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Oath of Pestilence" type="Archetype" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_PALADIN_OATH_OF_PESTILENCE">
        <supports>Sacred Oath</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Clad in grime-soaked armor and wielding rusting weapons, the Oath of Pestilence
                paladin spreads corruption, disease, and filth. Bound by an oath which infests their
                bodies with all manner of plagues, these heralds of decay lumber forward with unholy
                toughness and grim resolve.</p>
            <p class="indent">
                <b>Tenets of Pestilence</b>
            </p>
            <p>The tenets of the Oath of Pestilence emphasize the role of disease as a purifying
                element in the cycle of life.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>
                    <i>Strength in Resilience.</i>
                </b> Surviving hardship and plague
                make you stronger. Spreading these things causes strength to flourish.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>
                    <i>All Things Must Pass.</i>
                </b> Death is the natural conclusion
                of life. There is nothing unnatural or amoral about the ending of life.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>
                    <i>Might Makes Right.</i>
                </b> The laws of mortals mean nothing
                to poxes and plagues, they go where they wish and take what they want. So should
                you.</p>
            <div element="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_OATH_SPELLS" />
            <div element="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" />
            <div element="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_AURA_OF_RAMPANT_SICKNESS" />
            <div element="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_DISGUSTING_RESILIENCE" />
            <div element="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_PLAGUEBRINGER" />
        </description>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_OATH_SPELLS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_AURA_OF_RAMPANT_SICKNESS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_DISGUSTING_RESILIENCE" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_PLAGUEBRINGER" level="20" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Oath Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_OATH_SPELLS">
        <description>
            <p>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed in the Oath of Pestilence Spells
                table. See the Sacred Oath class feature for how oath spells work.</p>
            <h5>Oath of Pestilence Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr>
                        <td>Paladin Level</td>
                        <td>Spells</td>
                    </tr>
                </thead>
                <tr>
                    <td>3rd</td>
                    <td>
                        <i>bane, inflict wounds</i>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>5th</td>
                    <td>
                        <i>acid arrow, ray of enfeeblement</i>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>9th</td>
                    <td>
                        <i>flash fever, stinking cloud</i>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>13th</td>
                    <td>
                        <i>blight, confusion</i>
                    </td>
                </tr>
                <tr>
                    <td>17th</td>
                    <td>
                        <i>contagion, insect plague</i>
                    </td>
                </tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" level="3" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" level="3" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MELFS_ACID_ARROW" level="5" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="5"
                spellcasting="Paladin" prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_GHPG_SPELL_FLASH_FEVER" level="9" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD" level="9" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" level="13" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" level="13" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION" level="17" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="17" spellcasting="Paladin"
                prepared="true" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Channel Divinity" type="Archetype Feature"
        source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY">
        <description>
            <p>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity
                options. See the Sacred Oath class feature for how Channel Divinity works.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>
                    <i>Debilitating Fever.</i>
                </b> Your touch inflicts disease. Make
                a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach that isn’t a construct or
                undead. On a hit, the creature becomes diseased and is incapacitated for 1 minute.
                At the end of each of the diseased target’s turns, the target can make a
                Constitution saving throw. On a success, the target is no longer diseased, and the
                effect ends.</p>
            <p>Since this ability induces a natural disease in its target, any effect that removes a
                disease or otherwise ameliorates a disease’s effects apply to it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b>
                    <i>Entropic Infection.</i>
                </b> You can use your Channel Divinity
                to weaken a creature against entropic energies. As an action, you can force a
                creature of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you to make a
                Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, for the next minute the creature takes
                an additional 2d6 damage the first time it takes necrotic damage each turn. During
                this time, the creature loses resistance to necrotic damage if it has it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>You gain the following two Channel Divinity options. See the Sacred Oath
                class feature for how Channel Divinity works.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_DEBILITATING_FEVER" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature"
                id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_ENTROPIC_INFECTION" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Channel Divinity: Debilitating Fever" type="Archetype Feature"
        source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_DEBILITATING_FEVER">
        <description>
            <p>Your touch inflicts disease. Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your
                reach that isn’t a construct or undead. On a hit, the creature becomes diseased and
                is incapacitated for 1 minute. At the end of each of the diseased target’s turns,
                the target can make a Constitution saving throw. On a success, the target is no
                longer diseased, and the effect ends.</p>
            <p>Since this ability induces a natural disease in its target, any effect that removes a
                disease or otherwise ameliorates a disease’s effects apply to it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Debilitating Fever" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
            <description>Make a melee spell attack against a creature within your reach that isn’t a
                construct or undead. On a hit, the creature becomes diseased and is incapacitated
                for 1 minute. At the end of each of the diseased target’s turns, the target can make
                a Constitution saving throw. On a success, the target is no longer diseased, and the
                effect ends. Since this ability induces a natural disease in its target, any effect
                that removes a disease or otherwise ameliorates a disease’s effects apply to it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Channel Divinity: Entropic Infection" type="Archetype Feature"
        source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_CHANNEL_DIVINITY_ENTROPIC_INFECTION">
        <description>
            <p>You can use your Channel Divinity to weaken a creature against entropic energies. As
                an action, you can force a creature of your choice that you can see within 30 feet
                of you to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, for the next minute
                the creature takes an additional 2d6 damage the first time it takes necrotic damage
                each turn. During this time, the creature loses resistance to necrotic damage if it
                has it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet alt="Entropic Infection" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
            <description>You can use your Channel Divinity to weaken a creature against entropic
                energies. As an action, you can force a creature of your choice that you can see
                within 30 feet of you to make a DC {{pestilence:dc}}Constitution saving throw. On a
                failed save, for the next minute the creature takes an additional 2d6 damage the
                first time it takes necrotic damage each turn. During this time, the creature loses
                resistance to necrotic damage if it has it.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="pestilence:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="pestilence:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="pestilence:dc" value="charisma:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Aura of Rampant Sickness" type="Archetype Feature"
        source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_AURA_OF_RAMPANT_SICKNESS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 7th level, you emit an aura of contagion and virulence to a range of 10
                feet. When a creature within your aura makes an ability check, attack roll, or
                saving throw you can give that roll disadvantage as a reaction. Once you do, you
                can’t give another roll disadvantage using this feature until the start of your next
                turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>You emit an aura of contagion and virulence to a range of {{aura of rampant
                sickness:range}} feet. When a creature within your aura makes an ability check,
                attack roll, or saving throw you can give that roll disadvantage as a reaction. Once
                you do, you can’t give another roll disadvantage using this feature until the start
                of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="aura of rampant sickness:range" value="10" />
            <stat name="aura of rampant sickness:range" value="20" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Disgusting Resilience" type="Archetype Feature"
        source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_DISGUSTING_RESILIENCE">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, when you take damage which would reduce you to 0 hit points, you can
                choose to expend any number of hit dice. Roll those dice and subtract the result
                from the damage taken. If this reduces the damage to 0, you don’t take any damage.</p>
            <p>In addition, if you are killed your corpse violently explodes in a shower of pus and
                gore, dealing 8d6 necrotic damage to creatures within 20 feet of you that fail a
                Constitution saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take damage which would reduce you to 0 hit points, you can choose
                to expend any number of hit dice. Roll those dice and subtract the result from the
                damage taken. If this reduces the damage to 0, you don’t take any damage.&#13;
                In addition, if you are killed your corpse violently explodes in a shower of pus and
                gore, all the creatures within 20 feet of you must make a DC {{pestilence:dc}}
                Constitution Saving throw. On a failed, the explotion deals 8d6 necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Plaguebringer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Grim Hollow - The Players Guide"
        id="ID_GFG_GHPG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PESTILENCE_PLAGUEBRINGER">
        <description>
            <p>At 20th level, you become an avatar of plague, which gives you the following
                benefits:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You have resistance to necrotic damage and are immune to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are immune to the poisoned condition.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>